Guide to the Albert Hazen Wright Papers, 1820-1960
Hazen Wright, Albert Papers, 1820-1960
- Series III. Business Correspondence
  - O, 1940-45 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - O, 1953-66 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - P, 1910-19 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - P, 1920-29 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - P, 1930-35 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - P, 1936-39 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - P, 1940-43 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - P, 1945-49 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - P, 1950-59 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - P, 1960-66 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Palmer, E.L., 1917-34 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Plant Purchases, 1916-20 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Plant Purchases, 1916-23 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Plant Purchases, 1916-23 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Plant Purchases, 1918-20 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Q, 1920-39 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Q, 1940-66 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - R, 1904-19 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - R, 1920-29 (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - R, 1930-39 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - R, 1940-44 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R, 1945-49 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - R, 1950-66 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Raney, Edward C., 1935-46 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Rice, Donald T., 1924-34 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Rideout, Blanchard L., 1945-46 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Riley, William A., 1910-33 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ritchey, Paul H., 1943-47 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - S, 1906-10 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - S, 1911-19 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - M, 1920-24 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - S, 1925-29 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - S, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - S, 1931-34 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - S, 1935-40 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - S, 1940-43 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - S, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - S, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - S, 1946-48 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - S, 1949-59 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - S, 1960-66 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Shurman, Jacob Gould, 1910-17 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Schmidt, Karl, 1915-18 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Schmidt, Karl, 1921-33 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Schmidt, Karl, 1933-53 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Hobart, 1943-46 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Smith, Hobart, 1944-47 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - State Planning Board, 1936-37 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - T, 1910-19 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - T, 1920-29 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - T, 1930-43 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - T, 1944-45 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - T, 1946-47 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - T, 1948-59 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - T, 1960-66 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Charles E. Tuttle Co., 1943-44 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Trapido, Harold, 1935-38 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Trapido, Harold, 1938-43 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Trapido, Harold, 1939-40 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Trapido, Harold, 1941-49 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Trapido, Harold, 1943-62 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - V, 1929-65 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - V, 1908-34 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - V, 1935-45 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - V, 1946-50 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - V, 1951-64 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Van Hyning, O.C., 1928-32 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Viosca, Percy Jr., 1935-38 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - W, 1904-19 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - W, 1925-30 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - W, 1926-30 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - W, 1930-34 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - W, 1935-39 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - W, 1940-44 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - W, 1945-49 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - W, 1950-59 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - W, 1960-65 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - War Production Board, 1943-44 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Wright Family, 1953-63 (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - Weed, Alfred C., 1905-37 (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Wilder, Burt G., 1905-50 (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Y, 1914-37 (Box 13, Folder 62)
  - Y, 1944-66 (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Z, 1918-66 (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 65)
  - Micellaneous postcards (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1906-47 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1926 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1939-59 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1949-51 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1953-70 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence-A.A. Wright, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Old Northhampton.. ."Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence related to A.H. Wright's research, 1930-65 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Genealogical Material
  - Berridge Family (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Census Reports (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Conyn Family (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - John Dickson (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Downs Family (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Downs Family (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Grennelle Family (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Grennelle Family (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Harrington Family (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Harrington Family (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Harrington Family (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Harrington Family (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Irish (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Remington Family (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Willard Family (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Wright Family (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Wright Family (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Notes on Miller (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Albert Hazen Wright's Genealogical Notebook (Box 14)
  - The New England Historical and Genealogical Register, Jan., 1881 (Box 14)
  - "A Short Account of the Descendants of William Haskell of Gloucester, Mass.", 1896 (Box 14)
  - "Our Parents Delos C. and Emily A. (Hazen) Wright: Their Ancestry" Part I by A.H. Wright and A.A. Wright, 1964 (Box 14)
  - "Our Parents Delos C. and Emily A. (Hazen) Wright: Their Ancestry" Part II by A.H. Wright and A.A. Wright, 1964 (Box 14)
  - "Our Parents Delos C. and Emily A. (Hazen) Wright: Their Ancestry" Part II by A.H. Wright and A.A. Wright, 1964 (Box 15)
  - White Family (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - White Family (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - White Family (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - White Family (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Downs Family (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Downs Family (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Hazen Family (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Hazen Family (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Putnam Family (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Miller Family (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Rhoda Brooks (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Wright Family (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wright Family (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Wright Family (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Delos C. Wright (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Willard Family Association, 1959-65 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Moses Dewitt (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Questions (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Puzzles (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Taber Genealogy: Descendants of Joseph and Philip Sons of Philip Taber, 1952 (Box 15)
  - Notes and correspondence (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Willard Family Association (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Genealogical chart written by A.H. Wright (Box 4)
  - Genealogical Charts (Box 36)
  - Tabor papers and geneology (Box 63)
  - 2 Vols. “Our Parents” (Box 63)
  - 80TH Birthday (Box 64)
  - Golden Anniversary (Box 64)
  - Anna’s Passing (Box 64)
  - Family Bible (Box 65)
  - Albert’s Holy Bible (Box 65)
  - Book of Hospital and B-day cards (Box 65)
  - Book of Autographs (Box 65)
  - Poll Election Lists
    - Town Election-Town of Parma, NY, Mar. 1, 1853 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Annual Town Meeting-Parma, NY, Mar. 6, 1854 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Poll List for Fall Election, Nov.4, 1856 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Poll List, Feb. 15, 1854 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Poll List for Fall Election, Nov. 6, 1855 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Poll List, Nov. 3, 1857 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Annual Town Meeting-Parma, NY, Mar. 6, 1849 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Poll List for Fall Election, Nov. 3, 1857 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Annual Town Meeting-Parma, NY, Mar. 2, 1858 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Town Election-Town of Parma, NY, Mar. 2, 1847 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - List of Persons voting in the annual town meeting in Parma, NY, Apr. 16, 1839 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - List of Persons voting in the election at Parma, NY, Nov. 3, 1846 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Poll List for District 2-Parma, NY, Nov. 8, 1842 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 19 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Poll List of Town Meeting, Mar. 6, 1855 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Poll List Election District No. 1, Nov. 4, 1851 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Town Meeting-Parma, NY, Mar. 4, 1845 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - List of Election-Parma, NY, Nov. 5, 1844 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - List of Election-Parma, NY, Nov. 8, 1842 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Poll List for District 2-Parma, NY, Nov. 7, 1848 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Poll List for Districts 1 & 2, Nov. 7, 1854 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Poll List for District 1, Nov, 1853 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Poll List for District 2, Nov. 2, 1852 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Poll List for District 2, Nov. 5, 1844 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Poll List for Town Meeting-Parma, NY, Mar. 7, 1848 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Poll list for District No. 2, Nov. 4, 1851 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Poll List for District No. 1, Nov. 4, 1844 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Poll List, Mar. 5, 1850 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Poll List for District No. 2, Nov. 4, 1857 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous Poll Lists (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Road Warrants-Parma, NY, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Road Warrants-Parma, NY, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Road Warrants-Parma, NY, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Series V. Writings and Miscellaneous Papers
  - Sullivan Expedition Losses (Box 46)
  - Sullivan Expedition Losses (Box 46)
  - Sullivan Expedition Losses (Box 46)
  - Sullivan Expedition Losses (Box 46)
  - Negatives-Various Books (Box 46)
  - 'Ovid Bee' Transcripts, April 1859 (Box 46)
  - "Relation of Ezra Cornell to the N.Y.S. Agriculture College at Ovid" by S.H. Gage, January 11, 1924 (Box 46)
  - N.Y.S. Agricultural College, Misc. (Box 46)
  - 8 Vols. of Papers, 1902-1914 (Box 47)
  - 2 Vols. of Our Georgia Frontier (Box 47)
  - 8 Vols. of Papers, 1910-1938 (Box 48)
  - 7 Vols. of Papers, 1918-1941 (Box 49)
  - 8 Vols. of Papers, 1938 - 1953 (Box 50)
  - 1 Vol. Florida Ship Canal (Box 50)
  - 6 Vols. of Papers, 1953-1960 (Box 51)
  - 5 Vols. of Papers, 1960-1963 (Box 52)
  - 4 Vols. Sullivan’s Expedition (Box 57)
  - 6 Vols. on Sullivan’s Expedition (Box 58)
  - 1 Vol. Vertebrates of Cayuga Lake (Box 61)
  - 10 Books of N.Y.S. Maps and History (Box 61)
  - Hartt Letters (Box 62)
  - 2 Vols. Miscellaneous Papers (Box 64)
- Series VI: Snake Stories and Research
  - Snake Stories-595-I (Box 17)
  - Snake Stories 595a-864-II (Box 17)
  - Snake Stories 865-1227-III (Box 17)
  - Handbook of Snakes Vol. III (Box 17)
  - Handbook of Snakes Vol. III (Box 17)
  - Index (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Handbook of Snakes Vol. III (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Rough Drafts (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Research (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Research (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Research (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Manuscripts (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Part VI: "Snakes in Poetry" (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Part V: "Fear of Snakes" (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Part IV: "Snakes Charming" (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Part III: "Do Snakes Swallow Their Young?" (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Part II: "Snake Stories General and Unclassified" (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Part II continued (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Introduction and Part I (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Part I continued (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Part I continued (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Part I continued (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1937-49 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Drawings (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Drawings (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Negatives, drawings and photographs (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous plates of snake drawings (Box 18)
  - Memorandum of agreement, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Maps (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Sizes of snakes (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Sizes of snakes (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Sizes of snakes (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Sizes of snakes (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Mexican Border Species (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Notes (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Rough Draft (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Book Material (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - 3 Vols. on Snakes (Box 58)
  - 12 Vols. on Snakes (Box 59)
  - 15 Vols. on Snakes (Box 60)
  - 7 Vols. on Snakes (Box 61)
- Series VII. Frog Research
  - Frog Material (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Frog Material (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Measurement of Frogs (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - "Vocal Sacs of the Frogs of U.S.A." (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Notes of S.C. Bishop on Mink Frogs (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Photographs (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Pictures of toads and frogs (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Data for egg chart (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Photographs and other material (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - A Watercolor picture to A.H. Wright from Bill Sargent (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Material on tadpoles (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Pictures of toads and frogs (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 22)
  - Pictures of frogs and toads (Box 22)
  - Drawings (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Photographs (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Pictures (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Pictures (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Pictures (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous material (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1 Vol. frogs US and Canada, 1930 (Box 53)
  - 7 Vols. on frogs, 1942, 1949 (Box 53)
  - Frogs and Toads, 1930 (Box 54)
  - 3 Vols. Monograph Frogs (Box 54)
  - 1 Vol. General plates of Frogs (Box 54)
  - 12 Vols. on Frogs and Tadpoles (Box 55)
  - 10 Vols. on Okefinokee Frogs and Reptiles (Box 56)
  - 5 Vols. Okefinokee Frogs (Box 57)
- Series VIII: Research Notes
  - General
    - Color and Description of Turtles (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Color and Description of Turtles (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Amphibian Notes (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Slides (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Notes (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Notes (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Notes (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Papers-I, 1965 (Box 23)
    - Papers-II, 1965 (Box 23)
    - New York Historical Source Studies, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Scientific Papers by other authors (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Scientific Writers Notes (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Scientific Writers Notes (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Early Records of the Wild Turkey", July, 1914 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Canadian Herpetologists Toronto (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Newsclippings from the Hilton Record, Hilton, NY, five articles by A.H.W.'s mother and one by Emily Ann Hazen Wright, 1958 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper article, July 4, 1924 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Views and Recommendations and Letters, 1933 and 1937 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Garden notebook (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Notebook, 1930-31 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - World travel notes (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Birds of North America (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Entomology Journals (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Periodicals in and not in Cornell Libraries (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Texas Desiderata (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Desiderata on North American Travel (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - West Virginia (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Rafinesquiania (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - American Historical Periodicals (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - New York State History
    - Ithaca and Cayuga Heights Research (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - New York State History-Clinton Dewitt (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - New York State History-Robert Sutcliff (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - New York State History-Richard Parkinson (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - New York State History (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and newsclippings related to Old Northampton book (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Irises
    - Irises, 1926-31 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Irises (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Photographs of irises (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Iris Books I and II, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Iris Photographs, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Iris Photographs, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - Iris Photographs, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Iris Notes (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Iris Notes (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Iris Notes (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Iris Notes (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Iris Correspondence, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Iris Correspondence, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Iris Sellers Correspondence, 1926-27 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Iris Sellers Correspondence, 1926-28 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Iris Sellers Correspondence, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Journal Entries (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - "The Genus Costus in Central America" (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - "Plants from Tierra-del-Fuego" (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - "Hesketh Prichard Through the Heart of Patagonia" (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Entomological Reports (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Rough drafts and miscellaneous material (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Ornithology Record book (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Notebook and note cards (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Postcards (Box 19)
    - Notebooks (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Notebooks (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Notebooks, 1904-16 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Notebooks, 1921-23 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Notebooks, 1921-28 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, 1922-25 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Notebooks, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Notebooks, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Notebooks, 1928-30 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Notebooks, 1928-31 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Notebooks, 1933-34 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Notebooks, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks, 1935-36 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Notebooks, 1941-42 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous material (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Orchid photographs (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Peonies notes (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Upland Drive Garden-miscellaneous notes (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Upland Drive Garden-miscellaneous correspondence, 1920-23 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Upland Drive Garden-rose notes (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Upland Drive Garden-peony test (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Orchid photographs (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Vol. 1 and 2 on Dwarf Bearded Iris (Box 65)
  - Field Notebooks
    - Mammalogy Notes (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Mammalogy Notes (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Mammalogy Notes (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Mammalogy Notes (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Mammalogy Notes (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Field Notebook, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Field Notebook, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Field Notebook, 1907 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Field Notebook, 1907-08 (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Field Notebook, 1908-10 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Field Notebook, 1910-13 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Field Notebook, 1913-15 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Field Notebook, 1914-15 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Field Notebook, 1915 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Field Notebook, 1917 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Field Notebook, 1917-19 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Field Notebook, 1925-27 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Field Notebook, 1928-30 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Field Notebook, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Journal (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Notebook (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Natural History Notes from History Annals (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Maps of Ithaca and other parts of New York State (Box 26)
    - H.D.Reed's Field Notebook, 1904 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - H.D.Reed's Field Notebook, 1900 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - H.D.Reed's Field Notebook, 1899 (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Series IX: Lizard Research
  - Common Names of Lizards (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Common Names of Lizards (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Worksheets and keys of lizards (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - List of lizards and legends for plates (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography worksheets (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography worksheets (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Lizard book (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Lizard book (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Lizard book (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Lizard worksheets (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Gehlbach's material on lizards (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Key to the Genera of U.S.A. lizards (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Plates (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Notes (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Notes (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Notes (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Notes (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Lizard and toad notes (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of lizards for book-Part I (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of lizards for book-Part I (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Photographs of lizards for book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Lizard book-Part I (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Lizard book-Part I (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Lizard book-Part I (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Lizard book-Part II (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Lizard book-Bibliography (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Lizard book-Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Lizard book-Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Lizard book-Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Lizard book-Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Lizard book-Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Lizard Plate (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Notebook (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Notes (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Notes (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Research notes (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Maps (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Notes-Cnemidophorus tessellatus (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Notes- Cnemidophorus hyperythrus (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Notes- Cnemidophorus melanostethus (Box 28, Folder 9)